Preliminary Inventory to the John Wesley Masland Papers, 1945
Hoover Institution Archives
John Wesley Masland Papers,
1945
45005
Masland, John W. (John Wesley), 1912-1968.
21 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope. (8.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, minutes of meetings, directories, notes, and printed matter, relating to the United Nations Conference on International Organization at San Francisco and the founding of the United Nations.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United Nations Conference on International Organization (1945: San Francisco, Calif.)
Container List
- United Nations Conference On International Organization
  - General miscellaneous: Preamble, purposes, principles, Chairmen of Committees, Organization of Conference, General (English), Part 1.
  - General (English), Part 1, General (English), Part 2-3.
  - Comments and proposed amendments concerning the Dumbarton Oaks proposals, May 7, 1945 (English).
  - Dumbarton Oaks proposals, May 14-June 1945 (foreign languages).
  - Journal, April 25-June 21, 1945; San Francisco Charter, June 25, 1945; Plenary, April 26-June 24, 1945.
  - Commission 1 - General Provisions (English).
  - Commission 1 - General Provisions (English - foreign languages).
  - Commission 2 - General Assembly (English - foreign languages).
  - Commission 3 - Security Council (English - foreign languages).
  - Commission 4 - Judicial Organization, Preparatory Commission, Advisory Committee of Jurists, Executive Committee, Credentials Committee.
  - Coordination Committee.
  - Steering Committee, Secretariat papers (Masland), Precis of Committee Proceedings, May 5-June 22, 1945.
  - Delegation Chairmen, Executive Secretary, New York Times-S. F. Chronicle, April 26-June 22, 1945, opening and closing day programs, verbatim minutes opening session.
  - Commission 1 - General Provisions ms, U.N. miscellaneous, directory of those attending.
  - General (French - 2 folders).
  - Commission 1 - General Provisions, Commissions 2-4 (French).
  - Commissions 1-4, Commission 3 - Security Council (French).
  - Commissions 2-3 - Plenary and miscellaneous, Commission 4 - miscellaneous.
  - Commission 4 (French and Chinese); Coordination Committee, Commission 4 - Judicial Organization, Executive Committee, General (Spanish); General.
  - Countries at the U.N. Conference (Russian); General (Russian).
  - Commissions and General (Russian), Commissions 1-4 (Russian).